Welcome to the Academic Services Orientation for new international students.
My name is Dr. Chen, and I'll be your guide this afternoon.
This session is designed to help you get familiar with the resources available on campus.
The Writing Centre offers free one-on-one tutoring for any course that involves written assignments.
Appointments can be booked online and walk-in sessions are available on Wednesday afternoons.
Our academic advisors are here to help you plan your course schedule each semester.
If you're having difficulty with any of your classes, we strongly encourage you to reach out early.
The library provides access to thousands of academic journals and databases through its online portal.
Research workshops are held every two weeks to help students develop their information literacy skills.
International students who need additional language support can visit the English Language Resource Centre.
The centre provides conversation groups, pronunciation workshops and academic writing seminars throughout the semester.
Students who are struggling with time management or study strategies may benefit from our peer mentoring programme.
Each mentor is a senior student who has been trained to help others develop effective learning habits.
The counselling office on the third floor offers confidential support for students dealing with stress or personal challenges.
We understand that adjusting to a new academic environment in a different country can be overwhelming at times.
That's why we've created a comprehensive support network that addresses both academic and personal well-being.
All registered students are automatically enrolled in the health insurance plan which covers most medical services on campus.
If you experience any issues with your enrolment or financial aid, the Registrar's office can assist you during business hours.
I'd like to remind everyone that maintaining a minimum grade point average is required to keep your scholarship and student visa status.
Please don't hesitate to reach out to any of the offices I've mentioned today, as we are all committed to helping you succeed in your academic journey here.