Good afternoon, and welcome to the biology lab.
Before we begin, I'd like to go over some important safety rules.
Safety goggles must be worn at all times during experiments.
Lab coats are available in the cabinet next to the door.
Never eat or drink anything while you are working in the laboratory.
All chemicals should be handled with gloves to avoid skin contact.
The emergency eyewash station is located right behind the instructor's desk.
If you accidentally spill any chemicals, notify your instructor immediately.
Fire extinguishers are mounted on the wall near both exits of this room.
Make sure you know the location of the nearest emergency exit before starting your work.
Used materials must be disposed of in the designated waste containers, not in the regular trash.
Biological samples should always be stored in sealed containers and clearly labeled with your name.
When using a microscope, make sure the lens is clean before placing your slide on the stage.
Each group is responsible for cleaning their workstation at the end of every lab session.
If the fire alarm goes off during an experiment, turn off all equipment and exit through the nearest door.
You are required to complete the online safety quiz before you will be allowed to participate in any lab activities.
Proper ventilation is essential when working with volatile substances, so always use the fume hood provided.
In the event of a chemical burn, immediately rinse the affected area with cold water for at least fifteen minutes.
All lab reports must follow the standard format outlined in the course syllabus and be submitted by the end of the week.
If you have any questions about today's procedures or the equipment we'll be using, please raise your hand and I'll come over to help.