Welcome to the campus bookstore.
We sell textbooks and school supplies.
New books are on the first floor.
Used books are cheaper and easier to find.
You can find notebooks and pens over there.
The checkout counter is near the front door.
We accept both cash and credit cards.
Student discounts are available with your ID card.
The return policy allows exchanges within two weeks.
Please keep your receipt if you want a refund.
Our store hours are from nine to six on weekdays.
We also have a small cafe in the back corner.
You can order coffee and sandwiches while you browse.
The bestseller section is right next to the main entrance.
We carry a wide selection of academic journals as well.
If we don't have a book in stock, we can order it for you.
Online orders can be picked up at the service desk downstairs.
During finals week, the store stays open until ten at night.
There's a study lounge upstairs where you can read before buying.
Feel free to ask any of our staff if you need help finding something.