Good morning and welcome to the Natural History Museum.
Today's tour will take about an hour and a half.
We'll begin with the geology exhibit on the ground floor.
This collection features rocks and minerals from around the world.
The crystal display in the center was donated by a local university.
Please do not touch any of the items behind the glass.
Photography is allowed, but flash photography is not permitted in this area.
Moving on, we'll visit the marine biology section on the second floor.
You'll notice a full-size model of a blue whale hanging from the ceiling.
This exhibit explains how ocean currents affect the migration patterns of sea creatures.
Researchers have found that rising ocean temperatures are threatening coral reef ecosystems.
The interactive displays allow visitors to explore deep-sea environments through virtual reality.
Next, we'll head to the dinosaur wing, which is our most popular attraction.
The skeleton you see here belongs to a Tyrannosaurus rex discovered in Montana.
Scientists believe this particular specimen lived approximately sixty-five million years ago.
Recent studies suggest that some dinosaurs may have had feathers rather than scales.
The fossil preparation lab is visible through the window at the end of this hallway.
Our paleontologists are currently working on a newly discovered species from South America.
Before we move on, feel free to take a closer look at the exhibits and ask any questions.
The gift shop near the exit carries books, models, and educational kits related to everything you've seen today.