Hi there, welcome to the dining hall.
We serve breakfast, lunch, and dinner.
Breakfast starts at seven thirty every morning.
You can pick up a tray at the entrance.
The salad bar is on your left when you walk in.
Hot meals are served at the counter straight ahead.
Today's special is grilled chicken with roasted vegetables.
All drinks are included with your meal plan.
You can refill your water bottle at the station over there.
Please return your tray to the drop-off area when you're done.
We have a vegetarian section with fresh options every day.
If you have any food allergies, please check the labels on each dish.
The dessert table is next to the beverage station near the window.
We try to use locally grown ingredients whenever they are available.
Students with a meal plan can eat here up to three times a day.
Guest passes can be purchased at the front desk for five dollars each.
The dining hall gets really busy around noon, so you might want to come a little earlier.
On weekends, we offer a special brunch menu from ten in the morning until two in the afternoon.
If you have any suggestions about the menu, there's a feedback box right next to the exit.
We hope you enjoy your meals here, and please don't hesitate to ask the staff if you need anything at all.